GIANNI TALLARITA

DATA SCIENTIST • TORCHIARA (RELOCATING TO BARCELONA, SPAIN), ITALY • +393515506523

• DETAILS •

Torchiara (relocating to Barcelona, Spain) Italy +393515506523 gianni2k@gmail.com

Date of birth 18/01/1987

• LINKS •

Personal Website + Portfolio

LinkedIn

• SKILLS •

Data Analysis

SQL

Machine Learning

Python

Wolfram Language

Large Language Models

Cloud Computing

LANGUAGES

English

Spanish

Italian

PROFILE

Data-Scientist, Machine Learning Engineer and Theoretical Physics PhD researcher with over 30 published papers. Experienced in using Machine Learning for advanced problems. Certified cloud associate for both Azure and AWS. Certified LLM training. Python, SQL and Wolfram language expert.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Associate Professor at Universidad Adolfo Ibáñez, Santiago de Chile

April 2015 — Present

Associate Professor of theoretical Physics. Published over 30 Q1 reviewed papers. Raised over 200k USD in research funding. Won "Best Young Researcher" prize twice. Supervised 2 Master Thesis students and a PhD student.

PostDoctoral Researcher at Centro Estudios Cientificos (CECs), Valdivia

October 2013 — April 2015

Published several papers in String Theory. Gave countless seminars at reknown and prestigious international conferences.

PostDoctoral Researcher at Universidad Nacional de La Plata, La Plata

April 2012 — April 2013

Published several papers in String Theory. Gave countless seminars at reknown and prestigious international conferences.

Summer Intern at Bank of America, London

June 2008 — September 2008

Implemented the automatic startup system check of all bank systems using shell prompts.

Systems Engineer at Ultra Electronics, Cambridge

June 2006 — September 2006

Developed the accelerometer system of anti-noise systems on commercial airplanes.

EDUCATION

PhD, Queen Mary University of London, London

October 2008 — January 2012

Masters of Science, University of Cambridge, Cambridge

March 2004 — September 2008

Masters in Data Science, Universidad Adolfo Ibáñez, Santiago

March 2023 — Present

CERTIFICATES

Azure ML Associate, Microsoft

AWS Cloud Practitioner, Amazon

Large Language Models: Application through Production, edX / Databricks